naturalhandyman.com 2000-04-08

# Privacy Statement

## Privacy Statement for The Natural Handyman

Internet user privacy and confidentiality is of the utmost importance to all of us at **The Natural Handyman**.  Our reputation and integrity is directly related to the trust we have with our clients and customers. Please find below a description of how **The Natural Handyman** strives to protect the privacy of Internet users, and maintain the Internet as a highly credible medium.

**User Information**

All users who visit **The Natural Handyman** website retain complete anonymity. We do not acquire or collect any personal information about you. Your name, address, phone number, and email address all remain your private properties. **The Natural Handyman** does, however, collect information which is specific to how you use the Internet. 

Our  servers note non-personally identifying details such as, but not limited to, the server you are logged onto, the geographic location of the ISP you use, the type of browser you use, and your IP address. This information is obtained solely for the purpose of determining the number of visits each of our pages receive, how much time our visitors spend viewing our articles and home many pages each of our visitors view.  This information is pooled for statistical purposes.

There are instances where a user may provide specific personal information when filling out a form on our site.  This information is kept in absolute confidence and is not shared with any other organization.  Furthermore we do not collect or sell the email addresses or demographic information of our visitors. 

**The Cookie Principle**

**The Natural Handyman** uses cookies for collecting such general information as how many people visit our site, how long they stay, and how many pages they view.  No personal information is obtained with the cookies.  Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that use if you desire.

#### Advertising On Our Site

**The Natural Handyman** uses outside ad companies to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information.

#### External Links

This site contains links to other sites. **The Natural Handyman** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

#### Contests

Now and then **The Natural Handyman** runs contests in which we ask visitors for contact information (like email address).

Contact information from our contests is used to contact the winner or winners when necessary.  Entering our contests does not place the entrant on any email list, nor is this information given or sold to anyone.

#### Special Relationships

**The Natural Handyman** shares content with other websites.  We do not, however, share any information given to us by users of our site.

#### Security

**The Natural Handyman** has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.  Email messages sent to us do not reside on a networked server and are inaccessible except for authorized persons.  Our subscriber lists are secured from unauthorized viewing or "harvesting".

**Disclosure**

**The Natural Handyman** has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. If you have any questions pertaining to this privacy policy and its contents, please direct your correspondence to [comments@naturalhandyman.com](mailto:comments@naturalhandyman.com).

We reserve the right to change our policy from time to time. A revised policy will apply to information collected after the date the policy is changed.
